[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
Next we'll describe the pruning procedure which
وسنقوم بعد ذلك بوصف إجراء التقليم،
takes this cost function that we describe and
والذي يتناول دالة التكلفة والتي وصفناها
uses it to throw away decisions in the tree that were not that important.
ويستخدمها للتخلص من القرارات في الشجرة والتي لا تعتبر مهمة.
The idea is pretty simple, consider a split in the decision tree and usually we
والفكرة بسيطة جدًا، وذلك باعتبار التقسيم في شجرة القرار
start from the bottom, so we'll start here with this candidate split to prune.
ونبدأ غالبًا من الأسفل، وسنقوم بالبدء من خلال هذا التقسيم المرشح للتقليم.
Should we split on term after we split first on credit and
هل يجب علينا التقسيم على الأجل، بعد أن نقوم بالتقسيم أولاً على الإقراض
then on the income mm, should we do that split or not.
ومن ثم التقسيم على الدخل، هل يجب علينا القيام بهذا التقسيم أم لا؟
Well we can use our cost function to figure out what to do.
حسنًا، يمكننا استخدام دالة التكلفة لاكتشاف ما الذي يجب أن نقوم به.
So let's say that the tree that showed everything here
ودعونا نقول إن الشجرة التي تُظهر كل شيء هنا،
has an error of 0.25 in the training data, but
بها خطأ يساوي 0.25 في بيانات التدريب،
we're trying to decide whether to split or not.
ولكننا نحاول تحديد هل نقوم بالتقسيم أم لا،
Well, let's see how many leaves we have.
حسنًا، دعونا نرى كم عدد الأوراق التي لدينا.
We have one, two, three, four, five, six leaves and if we use a lambda of 0.3,
لدينا 1 2 3 4 5 6، لدينا ست أوراق، وإذ استخدمنا λ والتي تساوي 0.3،
then the total here, the error plus lambda times the number
ومن ثم فإن العدد الكلي سيكون هنا عبارة عن، الخطأ (T) + λ (λ) مضروبًا في عدد الأوراق ،
of leaves will be 0.25 plus 0.18 which is 0.43.
حيث ستكون، 0.25 + 0.18 والتي ستساوي 0.43.
So that's the total, grand total here.
ولذا، فهذا هو الإجمالي، المجموع الكلي هنا.
Now let's see what happens after we do the pruning, if we were to do the pruning.
ولهذا، دعونا نشاهد ماذا يحدث بعد أن نقوم بالتقليم، إذا قمنا بالتقليم.
So if we were to do the pruning, let's say that the smaller tree is being
إذا كان علينا القيام بالتقليم، فدعونا نقول إن الشجرة الأصغر تم تقليمها،
pruned where this last year has been pruned has slightly higher training error.
وكان بها خطأ تدريب أكبر قليلاً، عندما تم تقليمها العام الماضي،
So, training error min up to 0.26 and you're like, should I really do it?
ولذا، فإن الخطأ في التدريب يصل إلى 0.26، ويكأن لسان حالك يقول، يجب حقًا أن أقوم بذلك.
Well let's look at the number of leaves.
حسنًا، دعونا نشاهد عدد الأوراق،
Its one, two, three, four, five leaves, and so we're here five leaves and
وهي 1 2 3 4 5، بدلاً من 6، ولذا فلدينا هنا 5 أوراق
say, okay, we have five leaves instead of six, so one less leaf.
وتقول حسنًا، لدينا هنا 5 أوراق، بدلاً من 6، لذا فهي أقل بواحدة،
The training error went up a little bit,
وسيزيد الخطأ في التدريب بمقدار بسيط.
but if you do five times 0.3, which is rounded, you get 0.15.
ولكن إذا قمت بضرب 0.5 في 0.3 والذي هي عبارة عن λ، فستحصل على 0.15.
You add that to 0.26, you get a grand total of 0.41 and
وإذا أضفت هذا الناتج إلى 0.26 فستحصل على مجموع كلي يساوي 0.41،
magically say this new tree Tsmaller is looking promising.
وستقول بدهشة غن هذه الشجرة الجديدة (Tsmaller)، تبدو واعدة أكثر،
It has worse training error by a little bit but lower overall cost.
حيث إن بها خطأ في التدريب بنسبة أقل قليلاً، ولكن تكون أقل في المجمل.
And so since it has lower overall cost, we're going to end up pruning, good idea.
ولذا، بما أنها بها تكلفة أقل في المجمل، فسنقوم بالانتهاء من التقليم، وتلك فكرة جيدة.
So that's the kind of simplification that looks okay in a simple example, when you
وهذا نوع من التبسيط والذي يبدو مناسبًا من خلال مثال بسيط،
have a massive tree of tons of data, it's hard to imagine how this things can prune.
عندما يكن لديك شجرة ضخمة بها مجموعات كبيرة جدًا من البيانات، ويكون من الصعب تخيل، كيف سيمكن تقليم تلك الأشياء.
But it must happen,
ولكن هذا التقليم يجب أن يحدث،
otherwise you're going to have tremendous amounts of over fitting in decision trees.
وإلا سيكون لديك مقدار ضخمة من التطابق المفرط في شجر القرار.
We're not just going to do the pruning procedure for the very bottom of the tree,
ولن نقوم فقط بإجراء التقليم في أسفل الشجرة،
we're going to keep going up the tree and revisit every decision that we've made in
بل سننتقل إلى أعلى الشجرة، ونتوجه مرة أخرى إلى كل قرار قمنا به
the decision tree and say is it worth pruning, is this worth pruning it?
في شجرة القرار، ونقرر هل يستحق التقليم، هل ذلك يستحق التقليم؟
Is it worth pruning income after credit?
هل ذلك يستحق القيام بتقليم للدخل بعد الإقراض؟
Is it worth pruning term after credit?
وهل يستحق تقليم الأجل بعد الإقراض؟
Is it worth pruning credit itself and just have the root node?
وهل يستحق تقليم الإقراض نفسه، والحصول فقط على العقد الجذرية؟
So we're going to check all those out and then find
ولهذا سنقوم بالتحقق من كل ذلك،
the best tree after this pruning procedure and output that as our solution.
ومن ثم نعثر على أفضل شجرة بعد القيام بإجراء التقليم، ويكون ذلك كحل مُخرج لدينا،
For completeness, I've included here the full algorithm for
وللإتمام، سأقوم هنا، بتضمين الخوارزمية لبناء شجرة قرار
building up a decision tree using pruning.
باستخدام التقليم.
It's a little bit more contrived, I'll leave you this reference for
وإنها مستنبطة بشكل أكثر قليلاً، وسأترك هذا لك كمرجع،
those who want to implement it themselves, but it's relatively simple to
لمن يريد تطبيق ذلك بنفسه، ولكن تطبيقها يعتبر بسيطًا نسبيًا،
implement and not that different than what you might have done in the regular case.
وليس مختلفًا عما قد تقوم به في الحالة العادية.
This kind of idea is fundamental though and
هذا النوع من الأفكار هو أساسي،
it's used in every decision tree learning approach out there with small caveats and
ويستخدم في كل طريقة تعلم لشجرة القرار ، مع وجود تحذيرات وتغيرات بسيطة
changes in the parameters, but overall, same idea.
في المعلمات ولكنها في المجمل، نفس الفكرة.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]